chicagobooth.edu 2019-04-25

# Privacy Notice | The University of Chicago Booth School of Business

Last Updated: June 19, 2018

The University of Chicago Booth School of Business (Chicago Booth) has created this Privacy Notice to explain why we collect particular information and how we will protect your personal privacy when you visit our websites, or otherwise engage with Chicago Booth (e.g., admissions/recruitment, delivery of educational programs, student services, research, public and private events) including through our London and Hong Kong locations. 

The following discloses our information collection, use, storage and other data processing practices for Chicago Booth.

Because we want to demonstrate our commitment to your privacy, this Privacy Notice provides the following information

## 1\. SCOPE OF THIS PRIVACY NOTICE

Chicago Booth is a part of the University of Chicago (University), a global educational institution, with affiliated entities, business processes, management structures, and technical systems that cross international borders. 

This Privacy Statement applies to Chicago Booth activities described above, as well as Chicago Booth websites, domains, services, applications, and products. Please note that certain Chicago Booth programs, products, or services may provide an additional privacy notice or statement that supplements this Privacy Notice. 

Privacy practices related to Chicago Booth alumni and development activities are addressed in a separate privacy notice, maintained by the University’s Office of Alumni Relations and Development. To access this notice, please [click here](http://ard.uchicago.edu/privacy-policy/). 

## 2\. COLLECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION 

Personal information is any information that personally identifies you or from which you could be identified. This may include your name, physical address, telephone number, email address, social security number or other numerical identifier and IP address. 

Chicago Booth may collect your personal information through your access and use of websites, web-based applications (e.g., inquiry forms, student applications, event registration, surveys), or mobile applications, during conversations or correspondence with Chicago Booth representatives, or when you complete an online application or inquiry form. 

### PROCESSING OF SPECIAL CATEGORIES OF PERSONAL DATA 

We also may request you provide other personal information from time to time (known as special categories by GDPR), such as your race/ethnicity, health information, sexual orientation, criminal history (if any), etc. If collecting such information, consent will be obtained as appropriate. 

### LINKS TO OTHER SITES 

Chicago Booth sites contain links to websites maintained or controlled by other parts of the University or third parties. Please note that when you click on one of these links, you are entering another website for which separate privacy practices and policies may apply. We encourage you to read the privacy-related information on the non-Chicago Booth sites as their policies or practices may be different than ours. 

## WE USE VARIOUS TECHNOLOGIES TO COLLECT INFORMATION:

### COOKIES 

The Chicago Booth website uses cookies. Cookies are text files that are stored in a computer system via an Internet browser. Visit the Cookie Notice page here for a detailed list of cookies used on the Chicago Booth owned sites.

### SOCIAL NETWORKING SITES

We may collect information about you in connection with social networking sites in several ways, such as: 

  * When you sign in to our website or application using a social networking account, such as a Facebook account. 
  * When you use one of our apps on a social networking site or choose to join (or “like”) one of our social networking pages on a social networking site (such as the Chicago Booth Facebook page. 

In these situations, the social networking site may make some information about you available to us. Please see the privacy policy for the social networking site to learn more. 

  * When you interact with one of our social networking pages or content, we may use cookies to learn which links you clicked. 
  * When you make information publicly available on your social networking page, we may collect that information. To learn more about the privacy practices of a social networking site on which you interact with us, please refer to the privacy policy for that social networking site. 

### INTERNET PROTOCOL ADDRESS 

We collect an IP address from all visitors to our site. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet. We use IP addresses to help diagnose problems with our server, administer our site, analyze trends, gather broad demographic information for aggregate use in order for us to improve the site, and deliver customized, personalized content. In some case we may use your IP address to customize content based on your location. 

### SOCIAL SHARING

If a user elects to use our referral services (social share, tell a friend, etc.) to inform others about our site, we may ask for the friend's name and email address. Chicago Booth may send the friend a one-time message inviting him or her to visit the site. Chicago Booth stores this information for the sole purpose of executing this one-time email.

### MESSAGE BOARDS

If you post, comment, indicate interest or complaint, or share personal information, including photographs, to any public forum on a Chicago Booth site, social network, blog, or other such forum, please be aware that any information you submit can be read, viewed, collected, or used by other users, and could be used to contact you, send you unsolicited messages, or for purposes over which neither you nor Chicago Booth have control. Chicago Booth is not responsible for the personal information you choose to provide in these forums. 

We will not facilitate the merging of your personally identifiable information with non-personally identifiable information collected through any advertising product or feature unless we notify you, and obtain your consent to, that merger. 

### ONLINE PAYMENTS 

We may collect credit card information from you for your application fee. A reputable third-party financial institution handles our credit card transactions. 

Whenever you transmit credit card information and other personal information through our site, the numbers and letters are scrambled using encryption technology. 

## 3\. HOW WE USE AND SHARE YOUR INFORMATION 

### PERSONAL IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION

Chicago Booth collects, stores, uses and otherwise processes personal information that you provide to us and information we collect about you to facilitate and manage your relationship (e.g., applicant, student, alumni, visitor) with Chicago Booth and better serve you during your engagement and interaction with Chicago Booth. In addition, Chicago Booth and the University may process your information in furtherance of other legitimate interests, such as 

(i) to analyze and improve our operations and processes, 

(ii) for outreach and marketing efforts, 

(iii) to conduct general research, 

(iv) when you choose to join programs such as events, clubs, or volunteer activities that are open to broader audiences, your contact information may be made available to participants in those programs, with the goal of facilitating contact among participants, 

(v) we are proud of our alumni and will publish alumni names, photos, and degree information (year, school, field of concentration, and dissertation title) from time to time either on one of our Chicago Booth web or social media sites, 

(vi) your Chicago Booth experiences, additional education information, and personal information such as address, telephone, email, spouse, and children may be included in [Chicago Booth’s community directories](https://community.chicagobooth.edu/welcome "Community Directory"). These directories are made available to other alumni, students, faculty, and staff to facilitate contact among members of the community, 

(vii) to fulfill other University responsibilities or purposes or 

(viii) to provide services to you. 

If we seek to use or process your information for a purpose not outlined in this Privacy Notice, we will request your prior consent as appropriate. Where we have sought, and you have provided, your express consent for a particular purpose, please note you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time by notifying us at the contact information below. 

## THIRD PARTIES

We may disclose your information to third parties as follows:

**Third-Party Service Providers and Partners:** At times Chicago Booth will use third parties to process your information on our behalf, for example to provide services, analysis, research and development, optimization and other internal purposes, including, without limitation, to compile usage data.

**University Affiliated Programs:** We may share your information with third parties that are affiliated with the University for the purpose of contacting you about goods, services, or experiences that may be of interest to you.

**Research and Studies:** We may share your information with third parties to provide services, analysis, research and development, optimization and other internal purposes, including, without limitation, to compile usage data. We require these third parties to comply strictly with our policies and require that they don’t use your personal information for their own business purposes without your consent.

**Required by Law:** We may share your information with third parties to the extent we are required to do so by law, court order, or subpoena.

**Emergency Circumstances:** We may share your information with third parties if, in our sole judgment, such disclosure is necessary to protect the health, safety, or property of any person.

**Consent:** We may seek your consent to disclose your information to third parties if we are required to do so. Where we have sought, and you have provided, your express consent for a particular purpose, please note you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time by notifying us at the contact information below.

**De-Identified and Aggregate Information:** We may use and disclose information about our applicants in de-identified or aggregate form without limitation.

**International Transfers:** We may transfer your information to third parties located in other countries. These transfers are made subject to appropriate technical safeguards and contractual provisions to ensure the security of your information.

Occasionally, we may contract with a third party to communicate on our behalf to the third-party's contacts. We don’t collect the email addresses or contact information from these third parties, and we don’t have access to their mailing lists. 

We may provide third party mailers with a suppression list of contacts to exclude from their email distribution list. In this situation, the third party doesn’t have permission to keep or market to contacts contained in these suppression lists, or to use them in any way other than as a suppression list for a mailing they are providing on our behalf. 

Other than as described above, we will not share your personal information with any third parties. 

## 4\. HOW YOU CAN CONTROL YOUR DATA COLLECTION 

You can use Google Ads Settings (<http://www.google.com/settings/ads/anonymous?>) to manage the Google ads you see and opt-out of interest-based ads. Even if you opt-out of interest-based ads, you may still see ads based on factors such as your general location derived from your IP address, your browser type and recent, previous searches related to your current search. 

You can also opt-out of anonymous website and/or application traffic behavior by clicking on the following opt-out privacy links: 

  * Adobe Analytics Opt-Out: <http://www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html>
  * AddThis: <http://www.addthis.com/privacy/opt-out>
  * CrazyEgg Opt-Out: <https://www.crazyegg.com/opt-out>. 
  * Facebook: <https://www.facebook.com/full_data_use_policy>
  * Google Analytics Opt-Out: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>
  * Marketo Opt-Out: [https://www.chicagobooth.edu/privacy-notice](https://www.chicagobooth.edu/privacy-notice/?marketo_opt_out=true)
  * Optimizely: <https://www.optimizely.com/privacy/>
  * Salesforce: <https://www.salesforce.com/company/privacy/>

You may specifically opt-out of data being collected and used by Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on. 

You can also opt-out from email communication by following the opt-out instructions included in such email newsletters and promotions. 

## 5\. CHILDREN’S PRIVACY 

Chicago Booth does not knowingly collect information from children as defined by local law, and does not target its websites or mobile applications to children under these ages. We encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children’s online and mobile activities and interests. 

## 6\. DATA RETENTION 

The need to retain data varies depending on the type of data. Chicago Booth will retain your personal data as long as necessary for the purpose of processing (e.g., record of attendance, archival, data analysis). We may also retain and use your information in order to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, prevent abuse, and enforce our agreements. 

## 7\. ACCESS TO AND ACCURACY OF YOUR INFORMATION 

Chicago Booth strives to keep your personal information accurately recorded. We have implemented technology, management processes, and policies to help maintain data accuracy. Chicago Booth provides individuals with reasonable access to personal information that they provided to Chicago Booth and the reasonable ability to review and correct it. To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity, such as requiring a password and user ID, before granting access to your data. To view and change the personal information that you directly provided to Chicago Booth, you can return to the web page where you originally submitted your data and follow the instructions on that web page, or use your CNET ID where enabled.

## 8\. INDIVIDUAL RIGHTS 

Various jurisdictions grant individuals rights regarding their data, including: 

  * the right to request access to your information held by the University; 
  * the right to have inaccurate or incomplete personal data rectified; 
  * the right to erasure of your information, provided there is no legitimate reason for the University to continue to process or retain the information; 
  * the right to restrict processing of your information in specific situations; 
  * the right to request provision of some elements of your information; 
  * the right to object to processing of your information, including to send you communications that may be considered direct-marketing materials; 
  * the right to object to automated decision-making and profiling, where applicable. 

All requests to exercise any of these rights should be made to the contact information below. 

## 9\. SECURITY 

Chicago Booth takes seriously the trust you place in us. All information provided to Chicago Booth is transmitted using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption. SSL is a proven coding system that allows your browser to automatically encrypt, or scramble, data before you send it to us. To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, to maintain data accuracy, and to ensure the appropriate use of the information, Chicago Booth utilizes reasonable and appropriate technical and administrative procedures to safeguard the information we collect and process. We protect account information by placing it on a secure portion of our website that is only accessible by certain qualified employees of Chicago Booth. Unfortunately, however, no data transmission over the internet is 100 percent secure. While we strive to protect your information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of such information. We strongly advise you not to share your password with anyone. 

## 10\. CONTACT INFORMATION 

If you have any questions about this Privacy Notice, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, you can contact: 

The University of Chicago Booth School of Business   
5807 S. Woodlawn Ave.   
Chicago, Illinois 60637 

You can also send an email to: [privacy@ChicagoBooth.edu](mailto:privacy@chicagobooth.edu)

## 11\. CHANGES TO THE PRIVACY NOTICE 

Changes may be made to this Privacy Notice and personal information may be used for new purposes. When significant changes are made to our privacy practices, they will be disclosed here. For your convenience please refer to the last updated date.
